hey everybody thanks for listening to
The Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski in this podcast we talk
about ways of growing in your life and
your business to be able to accomplish
more as a coach trainer and Mentor now
today I want to talk about something
that is really close to me as far as
something that we're doing I've been
doing webinars and trainings and and
coaching uh for the last year and a half
actually two years straight pretty much
where I speak on camera I connect with
people I record a weekly podcast I
create content and I do so very simply
very easily uh very confidently because
I've been doing it but it's a skill set
that I did not have initially you know
and I started uh creating content I was
not confident I felt super
self-conscious I I felt afraid of
looking silly and saying the wrong
things and was a perfectionist about
what I was thinking what I was saying
and I got too caught up in my head all
the time and so what I've learned is how
to get out of my head and really FL flow
from a flow State when I'm doing my
content and so there's a routine that I
actually go into depending on what type
of content that I'm creating number one
you know when it comes to a podcast like
this I often record them on the
coattails of a coaching or training that
I've just done with a group of people so
like for instance I just got done doing
a training with my group and now I'm
recording this podcast right here
because I'm coming off the high of that
training so that's one of the things
that I'll do other times is if I just
have a spark of an idea I'll go live on
my social media if I have a spark of an
idea I'll type it into my phone and I'll
have chat GPT sometimes help me reword
it if I'm not sure if it's coming across
very well so those are some ways of
creating content but what I really want
to focus in right now is on the
confidence to do video content and to
flow with that video content and if
you're struggling to get out of your
head here's a couple of techniques that
I've used that work that are foolproof
especially in the most anxiety inducing
instances of creating content so for me
if I'm doing a webinar or I'm doing a
challenge or something like that I have
a little bit of a level of anxiety
before doing so so I have a routine that
I go through where I do that number one
I eat something I eat something of some
kind to give me energy something that's
going to give me energy that's going to
sustain me so something that's a
carbohydrate something that has protein
and something that has fat something
balanced with fat proteins and
carbohydrates and so what that does is
that helps me inspires me and I it gets
the juices flowing in my brain then I
make sure that I drink an ample amount
of water and sometimes I might also have
a cup of coffee at the same time okay so
that kind of lights up my brain but then
the water helps hydrate me at the same
time then I might go take a shower or or
I might go swim or something like that
or I might go for a walk or walk on my
treadmill so this is actually a routine
that I used to do is I would eat
something drink coffee have some water
and then I'd go for a walk or I'd take a
shower and then as I came out of that I
would feel so excited and lit up that
that's when I would press uh into either
recording a piece of content or
delivering it live to people is coming
from that place and so find a routine
for you that makes you feel like a
million bucks that's one of the biggest
things is you can cultivate feeling like
a million bucks you can cultivate
feeling very confident and it can be
different for everybody was talking to a
friend of mine and I told him you know
listen he loves to worship and and and I
so I said worship before you make
content watch what happens it will flow
better for you one of the biggest things
that stops us from being successful is
worrying way too much what everybody
thinks about us and I get it it comes
from past experiences it comes from
situations where we got judged it also
comes from our own judgment towards
other
people you know if I look at a speaker
that's out there and I judge how they're
talking or how they're communicating or
things like that then I become
self-conscious and judgmental of what
I'm doing and if I've had a naysayer or
somebody who's mean say something to me
I might become self-conscious of how I
communicate or how I talk with people I
think we can all grow in our skill set
of communication we can all grow in our
ability to deliver content you know
today who you see in front of me to of
in front of you today is different than
who I was two years ago or even three
years ago when I started this podcast
you can see I'm a lot more confident I
flow a lot better I'm a lot more relaxed
when I'm talking uh and and and that has
come through working through what are
the things what are the limiting beliefs
in my mind and helping to calm my mind
another great exercise that I love to do
is I'll do a a meditation where I'll
breathe in and I'll focus in on my core
I'll breathe in I'll breathe out there's
an app it's called headspace.com that
can give you a guided meditation through
breathing that can actually help calm
you down internally especially if you
know that you got a lot of brain chatter
going on learning to calm that down is
effective when it comes to you being
able to teach speak and create cont
content I find that when I calm my brain
down it actually allows me to flow much
better and it flows from Instinct and
intuition okay and so that's what I do
anytime I'm making content is I have
sort of a direction that I'm going I
kind of chart my path but I don't
necessarily spend a lot of time coming
up with what I'm going to say I more
flow instinctually and
intuitively and so the way that we can
do that is we get into a state of mind
to where we're the happiest we they the
most confident where we feel like a
million bucks and for me as I want to
feel like I'm on top of the world I want
to feel like I am just celebrated by
everybody who's going to listen to this
that people are going to cheer me on and
I don't think about what the haters or
naysayers are going to say I can tell
you this that if you're ever creating
content and you're trying to justify
yourself to a hater or a
naysayer it's not going to flow very
well
it's going to come out awkward rather
imagine you're talking to a really close
Confidant and friend about something
that was happening to you and you know
that there's nothing you could do that
could be wrong by them there's nothing
you could say that could be wrong by
them and then you're just talking you're
just sharing you're just conversational
when you can deliver content from that
place of you're just having a
conversation you're just having fun with
it it becomes fun and less of a
task your content will become better
you'll impact people more you'll
actually string your ideas and thoughts
together
well and you'll create a better piece of
content a few things to be aware of
though when you do this be cautious to
not ramble too much again don't be super
self-conscious of that listen you're
talking to somebody who's like the king
of rambling you're you're talking to
somebody who is like I go off on a
tangent all the time on things sometimes
and I and and yet that is part of my
personality and I'm okay with that
because that is authentic for me but I
want to make sure that I'm landing the
plane as well as I'm flying it okay we
want to make sure that we're actually
headed in a direction and that we're
getting to the point as quickly as
possible one of the best exercises that
you can do is learning how to
communicate your thoughts with this few
words learning how to communicate your
your thoughts with this as simple of
words as possible and a great resource
for this that I love to use is chat GPT
again chat GPT can help us
reward uh difficult thoughts in very
simple ways so for instance I want to
show you how I use chat GPT to do
this can you
describe what it feels like to give a
talk or speech in a flow State as if you
talking to a fourth grader so I'm asking
GPT to explain this to a fourth grader
which make it very simple imagine you're
telling a story to a friend a story that
you really really like a lot when you
start talking you're super excited and
the words just come to you easily you're
not even thinking hard about what you're
going to say next it's like the story is
telling itself that's what it's like
when you're giving a speech or talk in a
flow State it's when you know so much
about what you're talking about and
you're so into it that everything just
feels easy you're not worried or scared
you're just having fun sharing what you
know it's like you're playing a game and
you're doing really well and you're not
even thinking about it you're just
enjoying the game that's how it feels
and I promise you you can get there with
your talking with your speech but often
times we overanalyze and overthink
trying to please people trying to sound
good enough trying to sound right trying
to make sure we say all the right
things one of the things we got to stop
being worried about is disappointing
other people and seeking other people's
approval here's the thing the people who
disapprove of you there's nothing you
can do to change their mind and the
people who love you there's nothing you
can do that's going to make them dislike
you so focus in on not worrying about
what nobody thinks about you when you go
out there and put content out there and
you will do better by doing that by
literally just
unlocking this I don't give any concern
to what somebody or people think about
me while I'm creating my
content and you'll do much better by
doing that now you might have to train
yourself to do this this here's one of
the ways that I encourage people to do
this is to borrow from other parts of
their life to borrow from other areas of
your life where maybe you felt
confident so for instance what is
something that you do on a daily
basis consistently already that you feel
really confident like you know your
stuff
about could be real estate could be
mortgages could be something like
that borrow that feel
when you're in your best State of Mind
in that area and bring it into the thing
that you don't feel confident in and it
might take you faking it and trying it
on initially it might also take having
some saying some
affirmations it might take you rewiring
your brain and programming it to be able
to operate in this way but I promise you
that it's worth it in the long run you
can accomplish anything that you set out
to do you can become an incredible
speaker you can become an incredible
content
creator but it's going to CH it's going
to take challenging maybe some of the
beliefs that you've
had so one of the number one things that
we got to be cautious of is how have we
judged other
people have we harshly judged others
when they're doing the thing that we
want to set out to do and then how do we
harshly judge ourselves how do we
harshly criticize
oursel what you want to do is you want
to be your biggest cheerleader and
really what I do is I take on the role
of if I'm thinking about my son so my
son is 10 months old he's learning to
walk but he falls down do I beat him up
and get angry at him when he falls down
my goodness that would be child abuse no
not at all I celebrate him when he falls
down because he at least gave it his
best shot and he gets all excited and
happy for falling down I'm training my
son by doing this to be
resilient and that's something that I
believe that we can train ourselves to
do as well to be resilient to actually
look at the fact that we don't fail at
things but rather they're always
learning experiences that are stepping
us up to the next
level you either reach your goal and do
excellent at it or you learn a lesson
and learning a lesson is incredible and
learning to embrace learning lessons
because of how they compound and how
they build is a superpower I believe
that no matter who you are no matter
where you are today you know I'm
thinking about some people that I've met
they just they're they're just like man
little me just does not feel confident
talking to
anybody well have you tried have you
tried to record something have you tried
to talk what are the thoughts that go
through your head who planted those
thoughts where have you come up with
those thoughts where did you come up
with thinking that way that you got to
do everything perfectly when you can
address those things
and you become okay with just giving
your best realize that you can always
improve over time and that you're never
going to be perfect and that's a good
thing and it's a good thing to not try
to be perfect but to rather just be
authentic and to connect and to be
curious and to make connections with
people that your best meant to
reach that becomes an incredible way of
creating content recording videos and
showing up as your best most powerful
confident self people are attracted to
who are confident people love to listen
to people who believe in and have
conviction about what they're talking
about be a person of conviction be a
person who projects an energy that I
believe in what I'm talking about and I
know my stuff even if you have
doubt now that might take some skill to
be able to do that but I I think we can
all agree we do that in other areas of
our life as well and you can do that as
well in this area I think so often we
get caught up in our head overthinking
trying to make sure that we say the
right things and do the right things and
show up and present ourselves in a
perfect way here's one of the biggest
things that I say and it's a little bit
controversial but I stand by it and I've
been saying it for years and I and I
believe it more today than I ever have
stop worrying so darn much about
your
reputation you let your reputation take
care of itself if you're a person of
integrity and of character your
reputation will be just fine not
everybody's going to like you and that's
okay you don't need everybody to like
you be willing to
just show up and even fail publicly and
that's okay and that's a good thing
because it's going to help you grow to
the next level you know for me I don't
give any concern as to what my
reputation is in 99% of any
situation and that's given me a lot of
Peace because I literally don't spend a
lot of time trying to cultivate and
curate what people think about me at all
I can let people can think whatever they
want about me people can think whatever
they want about me not curating my
reputation some of you have lost all
respect for me because I just said that
I'm okay with that I'm okay with
that because I know that those that are
meant to hear this message are going to
be impacted by it and it's going to
change their lives so listen if this
message has impacted you number one
please share it with somebody number two
consider joining my client growth
accelerator program when we open the
doors to it if you are a coach Mentor
trainer somebody who wants to create
multiple six figures and even seven
figures selling online courses training
coaching programs we walk you through
everything we got all the training
everything no stone unturned to help you
do that and you get to work with me and
meet with me on a live Zoom call every
single week to be able to build your
business together with us with our
community it's
incredible I believe in you and I know
that whatever you're going through right
now you can grow from this into the next
version of you that's going to be able
to accomplish your goals don't give up
don't quit too soon stay
consistent and grow your life everybody
I'll see you all next week we'll talk
[Music]
[Applause]
soon